PREETUMSING LUCHOWA (ASH)

Manning Road, Como, WA 6152 | ashwinluchowa@gmail.com | +(61) 0426 850 943

INTRODUCTION

Originally from Mauritius, I am a 34-year-old permanent resident with no visa-restrictions who has called Perth home for the past 8 years. In recent years, I have gained valuable experience in blue-collar roles, focusing on customer service, teamwork and problem solving. However, I am determined to pivot my career towards programming and web development, areas where my true passion lies.

I work efficiently as a team as well as autonomously and my previous experience has enabled me with the ability to adapt in any work environment. I am looking for an opportunity in my field as a web developer, preferably full-time, though I'm also open for internship opportunities to further enhance my expertise. I am available to work at any time and day, preferably giving 1 week of notice to my current employer.

EXPERIENCE

Kalkulas Brothers
Perth, WA
Store Clerk
Jan 2024 – Present

- Operating cash registers and handling customer transactions.
- Assisting customers on product selection and addressing customer's complaints.
- Ensures shelves are well-stocked and organized.
- Keep the store clean during and after closing time.
- Assisting the deli, making sure everything is well presented and ready to be sold, and assisting customers in decision making.
- Collaborate and communicate with colleagues to ensure smooth store operations.

Blue Collar People Baggage Handler

Perth, WA

June 2022 – <u>Dec</u> 2023

- Loading and unloading of luggage up to 32kg each during shifts ranging from 4 to 12 hours.
- Driving baggage tugs airside, carrying up to 6 ULDs while maintaining safety, security and adhering to regulations.
- Working in harsh weather conditions, such as heavy rain with limited visibility or under extreme heat.
- Handling customer's missing baggage / parcels daily, ensuring good customer service and solving customers' complaints.
- Using radio to communicate with supervisors and managers when given leaderhand role in terminal 3.
- I was able to load 3 big Qantas airlines by myself during a period when there was a worker shortage crisis in 2022. Each plane ranges from 150 to 200 luggage.

Security Officer / Crowd Controller

November 2019 - June 2022

- Static Guard (Liquor stores, mine sites, supermarkets, nightclubs, hotels & pubs). I helped prevent multiple theft attempts in multiple Woolworth stores.
- Detected underage teenagers with no eligible IDs during the sales of alcohol or venue entry. I also assisted my co-workers to diffuse bar fights.
- Was on the frontline during the pandemic and worked in multiple quarantine hotels, learning how to deal with a frustrated crowd and individuals.
- Crowd Controller (Large Events / Stadiums), up to 60,000 people.

GJK Facility Services

Perth. WA

July 2016 - February 2020

Commercial Cleaner

- Commercial cleaning, restoration and maintenance. Worked with clients such as the Housing Department, Westpac, Nab, Medibank, Reece Group, Quaker Oats and Jenny Craig under Award winning contractor, GJK Facility Services.
- Encouraging feedback from cleaning site managers and enforcing them.
- Drove to multiple cleaning sites daily, with a time window of 45 mins to 1hr available to clean each site, mostly autonomously.
- Training new cleaners and making sure they were adhering to work safety and maintaining cleaning standards.
- Was granted a certificate of appreciation from the contractor GJK.

Avant (Mauritius) LTD

Mauritius

Graphic Designer

July 2013 – December 2015

- Brainstorming and researching primary concepts and ideas provided by clients.
- Development of several marketing products such as posters, flyers, menu cards, business cards, letterhead, banners, signs, leaflets and logos.
- Preparing sketches and developing ideas further to meet clients' expectations.
- Amending or updating any changes requested by clients.
- Projects focused based on clients' limited budget and deadlines.
- Prepare directions and guides and save artworks for future clients' use.

EDUCATION

Diploma of Information Technology (Front End Web Development) (2023 - Present) North Metropolitan TAFE, WA

Master of Business Administration Project Management Specialisation (2018) Edith Cowan University, Australia

Bachelor of Arts (Hons) Graphic Design (2013)

University of Technology, Mauritius